

INTRODUCTION

I was born in China, I have been living in Palma de Mallorca, Spain for more than 18 years and have been working as a Golang backend engineer for more than 6 years, passionate about all technologies, frontend, backend, data science, Devops.

CONTACT

PHONE:

639433909

GITHUB:

https://github.com/zechao

EMAIL:

zechao158@gmail.com

TECH STACK

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGE:

STILL USING

Golang, Python, JavaScript, **USED** C#, JAVA

APPLICATIONS AND FRAMEWORKS:

STILL USING

Docker, PostgresSQL, K8S, Vue, AWS, gRPC, Rest, Datadog, Github

Redis, Pubsub, GraphQL, Consul, Elasticsearch, Kibana, Grafana, pprof

LANGUAGES

CHINESE: Native speaker

SPANISH: Fluent

ENGLISH: Conversational

ZECHAO JIN

GOLANG BACKEND DEVELOPER

WORK EXPERIENCE

AREX Markets and Bankable Golang Backend developer, Jun. 2021 until Now

As a backend developer on the LEADING team, my primary responsibilities are:

- Analysis, development, and maintenance different microservices that automate client onboarding flow using Golang, Rest, gRPC, Protobuf, Postgres and Amazon SOS.
- Integrating various third-party tools for Customer information validation, contract generation, e-signature, etc.
- Getting rid of the legacy code

TravelgateX

Golang Backend developer, Apr. 2018 - May. 2021

- Analysis, development, and maintenance of diverse HotelX microservices, that use GraphQL and REST APIs programmed in Golang, handling over 3 billion daily requests for hotel searches.
- Enhance system throughput by analyzing system using benchmark and pprof, improve system throughput by using in-memory and Redis caching.
- Use of Protobuf for internal service data exchange, Consul for microservices configuration, Elasticsearch for log storage and hotel static data, and tools like Kibana and Grafana for log querying and traffic monitoring.

Integration engineer, Aug. 2017 - Apr. 2018

- Connectivity programmer in the integrations team using C#,
- Responsible for analysis, development and testing for 4 Different APIs.
- Maintaining existing integrations.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Computer Science at Universtat de les Illes Balears, 2013 - 2019 The final degree project involves creating an artificial intelligence that plays Flappy Bird using a neural network and genetic algorithm.

Master of data science at Universitat Oberta de Catalunya, 2020 – 2022
The final project involved creating a deep learning model that addressed the GBSENSE 2022 challenge, specifically focusing on the Modulation Recognition Challenge.